

w: emilylee.org

Senior Designer, Art Director

I emily lee

I'm a designer and visual thinker, who enjoys creating and developing playful, engaging, interactive solutions. With over five years of experience designing for a variety of industries, including media and entertainment, healthcare, and finance, I've honed my ability to adapt my design aesthetic to a range of brands and styles. An ambitious and quick learner with boundless imagination, I am always excited to take on the next challenge, and to explore its creative possibilities.

experience

DirecTV | AT&T

Senior Designer New York, NY

Dec 2016 - Present

- Concepting and designing microsites, landing pages, campaign assets, and iconography for DirecTV and AT&T.
- Performing design QA to ensure products stay on-brand and true to design.

Isobar

Visual Designer New York, NY

Jan 2015 - Aug 2016

- Concepted and designed responsive websites, cross-platform mobile & TV apps (iOS, Android, AppleTV), consumer
 and internal-facing applications, presentations, pitches, and case studies.
- Conducted market research and concepted solutions to client briefs, representing them through self-directed moodboards and comps.
- Worked closely with UX designers and developers.
- Performed design QA to ensure products stay on-brand and true to design.
- Clients included NBC (USA, Bravo, Syfy, Telemundo, E!, Esquire, NBC Universo, Oxygen, Sprout, MSNBC), IntegraMed, LexMar Global, and Umpqua Bank.
- Actively attended conferences and workshops to stay on top of design and tech industry trends.
- Led monthly company-wide communications training group.

Situation Interactive

Interactive Designer New York, NY

May 2013 - Aug 2014

- Concepted and designed websites, landing pages, banners, rich media units, and social media campaigns.
- Storyboarded and developed flash banners, animations, and videos.
- Gave art direction to freelance designers.
- Performed design QA to ensure products stay on-brand and true to design.
- Worked closely with front-end developers, project managers, and account teams.
- Clients included The Metropolitan Opera, Roundabout Theatre, Ripley's Believe It or Not!, and Broadway musicals Wicked, Cinderella, Rock of Ages, Mama Mia!, Beautiful, Hedwig and the Angry Inch, and others.

GAIN Capital

Interactive Designer Bedminster, NJ

Jun 2012 - May 2013

• Concepted and designed flash banners, landing pages, widgets, infographics, social media assets, and style guides for FOREX.com and GAIN Capital.

- Managed the front-end development of FOREX.com landing pages and the TradeKing Forex microsite.
- Branded TradeKing trading platforms and mobile apps.
- Branded the Tradable for FOREX.com appstore.

Zemoga

Graphic Design Intern New York, NY

Jun 2011 - Aug 2011

- Concepted and designed on-brand materials, including a laptop case, notepads, and coffee packaging.
- Concepted and designed the Pixels & Pills blog and YouTube assets.

DoSomething.org

Graphic Design Intern New York, NY

Jan 2011 - Apr 2011

- · Concepted and designed wireframes, landing pages, and digital and print collateral for campaigns.
- Campaigns included "Stop Bullying" campaign, Aeropostale's "Teens for Jeans," HP's "Green Your School Challenge," and VH1's "Battle for the Bands."
- Created branding system for DoSomething.org's young social entrepreneur program BootCampX.

Nimli

Graphic Design Intern New York, NY

Nov 2009 - Feb 2010

- Concepted and designed banners and hero images.
- Retouched product photos for website.

education

Pratt Institute

M.S. Communications Design with Digital Design Emphasis

Honored as Distinguished Student New York, NY | May 2012

Carnegie Mellon University

B.H.A. Fine Arts & Creative and Professional Writing, with Honors

Minor in Business Administration Pittsburgh, PA | May 2009

honors

- Hilson Family Scholarship Award for Excellence, 2011
- American Assocation of Advertising Agencies Award, Operation Jumpstart Scholarship III Recipient, 2010 - 2011
- National Honors Scholar Society, 2009
- Dean's List, 2008 2009

skills

Design

- Art Direction
- Branding
- Concept Development
- Illustration
- UI
- Wireframing
- Responsive Design
- Marketing
- Motion
- Photography
- Packaging
- Print

Software

- Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects
- Sketch, InVision
- FinalCut Pro
- Keynote

Code

• HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript